<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>I Am Simme</title>
    <link>https://iamsim.me/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on I Am Simme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under the MIT license.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 17:12:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://iamsim.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coordinator Pattern</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/the-coordinator-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 17:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/the-coordinator-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Soroush Khanlou had a very interesting blog post a while back. In it he elaborates on his &amp;ldquo;coordinator pattern&amp;rdquo;. Its a very neat pattern in which you make all of your view controllers &amp;ldquo;flow agnostic&amp;rdquo;. Ie. they know nothing about the view controller hierarchy, when to push another view controller on the navigation stack, when to present a modal etc. All of that responsibility is delegated to a coordinator object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIStackView &#43; UITextView: Need constraints for Y position or height</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/uistackview---uitextview-need-constraints-for-y-position-or-height/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 19:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/uistackview---uitextview-need-constraints-for-y-position-or-height/</guid>
      <description>Just today I had to replace a UILabel with a UITextView. The label was inside of a UIStackView that had its position pinned to the bottom of another view, hence growing upwards. I&amp;rsquo;m doing all of this in Interface Builder btw. Just as I let go of the text view I&amp;rsquo;ve dragged in I see that ominous red circle with an arrow show up. Indicating that there&amp;rsquo;s some problem with my layout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift Equatable and Hashable</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/swift-equatable-and-hashable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 04:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/swift-equatable-and-hashable/</guid>
      <description>Swift provides a protocol that you can conform to to let the world know that your objects or structs can be compared and found equal or not: Equatable.
There&amp;rsquo;s also a protocol that allows you to use your objects as keys in a dictionary: Hashable.
In an app I&amp;rsquo;m working on I&amp;rsquo;m making some of the models (structs) conform to these procotols so that I can make diffing and such when refreshing the UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delegate calls wrapped in computed properties</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/delegate-calls-wrapped-in-computed-properties/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 11:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/delegate-calls-wrapped-in-computed-properties/</guid>
      <description>In the app I&amp;rsquo;m currently working I have a view that asks its delegate for the locale to use when rendering it&amp;rsquo;s model object.
The model has strings for all of the supported locales embeded in it and its just a matter of using the correct one when rendering.
The view itself can go through a number of different transitions which is why I need to ask the delegate a few times in a few different places for what locale to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting rid of typographic orphans with Swift</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/getting-rid-of-typographic-orphans-with-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 05:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/getting-rid-of-typographic-orphans-with-swift/</guid>
      <description>I composed this little Swift string extension to get rid of typographic orphans when rendering titles and such:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIStackView: Left align without stretching</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/uistackview-left-align-without-stretching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 12:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/uistackview-left-align-without-stretching/</guid>
      <description>UIStackView introduced in iOS 9 is awesome. However, as someone coming from the HTML/CSS programming world I sometimes find that it does not really match up with the mental model I have of how it should work.
There&amp;rsquo;s not any straight forward way of putting a number of absolutely sized items in a stack view and aligning them to either side. You can make them stretch to fill, distribute equally over the entire width of the stack view and you can center them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Debugging Node.js in Vim: update</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/live-debugging-node.js-in-vim-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 05:29:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/live-debugging-node.js-in-vim-update/</guid>
      <description>Just wanted to post a super quick update! Since posting my article a few months back there&amp;rsquo;s been some activity in the repository for the node-vim-debugger!
Looks amazing!
(If I was the kind of person to take credit for stuff I&amp;rsquo;d like to imagine that I sparked the burst of development creating an issue. Luckliy I&amp;rsquo;m very humble and would never do such a thing. ;))</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Résumé: or How I Accidentally Built a Static Site Generator</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/my-r%C3%A9sum%C3%A9-or-how-i-accidentally-built-a-static-site-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 18:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/my-r%C3%A9sum%C3%A9-or-how-i-accidentally-built-a-static-site-generator/</guid>
      <description>One thing that I did not really realize when I started freelancing was that potentially customers sometimes asks for a résumé. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t had a résumé in over six years. And I probably only wrote one or two before that.
So last week when I was approached by a company, that I really wanted to work with, asked for my résumé I sat down to write one. I opened up a new Google Docs file and started writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive Cocoa</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/reactive-cocoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 18:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/reactive-cocoa/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a nice article that explains Reactive Cocoa in a very succint way. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll ever really get into this style of programming (mostly because I don&amp;rsquo;t feel super comfortable basing an app entirely on third party frameworks). But I find it really fascinating and cool!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Node&#39;s Require and Browserify: Take 2</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/nodes-require-and-browserify-take-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 18:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/nodes-require-and-browserify-take-2/</guid>
      <description>A while back I wrote about taking advantage of Node&amp;rsquo;s require algorithm with Browserify. While I liked the concept of doing that I never really liked how it made things look file-wise.
Well. Turns out you don&amp;rsquo;t need to wrap your little module in a directory or give it a package.json!
Say you have a module called&amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s say do-some-math that exports some fancy math functions that are unique do your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Watch and I</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/my-watch-and-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 05:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/my-watch-and-i/</guid>
      <description>This started out as a 700+ word review of the Apple Watch. Then I read it and realized that I was just repeating what everyone else have already said about it. So, I threw it away. What remains is a short list of observations, still mostly echoing others.
 The try-on experience in the store was weird, but kind of fun. I went with the classic leather buckle. Comfort wise it&amp;rsquo;s comparable to the black sportband (which I also got).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIStackView and Autolayout</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/uistackview-and-autolayout/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 19:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/uistackview-and-autolayout/</guid>
      <description>Was about to tear my own hair off due to issue with UIStackView and autolayout. Here&amp;rsquo;s a simplified version of my view hierarchy:
- UIStackView - MyCustomView - UILabel - MyCustomView - UILabel - MyCustomView - UILabel  The stack view are laying the custom views out in a horizontal fashion. Now, whenever I added a constraint similar to this:
let xConstraint = NSLayoutConstraint(item: label, attribute: .Left, relatedBy: .Equal, toItem: self, attribute: .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS Storyboard Tips &amp; Tricks</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/ios-storyboard-tips--tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 19:46:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/ios-storyboard-tips--tricks/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending some time diving into iOS development for reals during my spare time the last couple of months. In this time I&amp;rsquo;ve come to learn a lot of things about storyboards, other than that they are pretty awesome.
Here are two things in particular.
Table View Data Sources and Delegates In the very first issue of objc.io they discuss how to make your UITableViewControllers lighter by moving data sources and delegates to separate objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac App of the Week</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/mac-app-of-the-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 17:43:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/mac-app-of-the-week/</guid>
      <description>My &amp;ldquo;Mac App of the Week&amp;rdquo;-award (not actually a weekly occurence) goes to Paw! Paw makes it super easy to try and debug web APIs!
You can save requests, group them, edit JSON in a nice way, easily exclude keys from JSON POST calls, view responses in different format, extend functionality with JavaScript. The list goes on.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever used Postman for Chrome or if you&amp;rsquo;re hacking away in your terminal with Curl, give Paw a go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Trello CSS Guide</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/the-trello-css-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 17:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/the-trello-css-guide/</guid>
      <description>A while back I saw the Trello CSS Guide swim around my Twitter timeline. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using that style of writing CSS ever since, I&amp;rsquo;ve even started to introduce it ever so slightly in the Bloglovin CSS (although converting a two year old project is not something you do in one go). I&amp;rsquo;ve found the guide to result in very maintainable CSS code. It&amp;rsquo;s even possible to make changes without being scared of breaking stuff, because it&amp;rsquo;s all so neatly namespaced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/on-getting-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 15:55:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/on-getting-things-done/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve made an effort recently to get better at getting things done. At work we already have a list of stuff to do but at home there&amp;rsquo;s an endless list of tasks that needs doing. It&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon to spend half of Saturday just &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo;.
Things have been on my Macs basically since it was launched. And on my iPhone since it was released on iOS a few years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jared Tries a Watch</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/jared-tries-a-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 19:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/jared-tries-a-watch/</guid>
      <description>My collegue-for-another-month-and-a-half Jared Sinclair went to an Apple Store and tried on a few watches.
I have been interested in the link bracelet and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if his comments make me more or less interested in one. Although I think that the price of it has already made me more interested in the classic buckle.
Most of all I just want Apple to announce a shipping date for Sweden! Come on guys!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wars to Come</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/the-wars-to-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 18:48:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/the-wars-to-come/</guid>
      <description>While the title is a Game of Thrones reference this post is not about the fantastic show on HBO. No, the title is a hint about my future. I mean, it might be a bit dramatic. But I&amp;rsquo;ve come to embrace that side of my writing. Anyway, I was just failing for ways to begin this article. Now that it has begun I can concentrante on getting to the point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking of Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/speaking-of-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 06:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/speaking-of-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>That last post made me want to do a post similar to what Stefan Laketa has done and write a more comprehensive list of the podcasts I currently listen to. Mainly for my own sake to look back at in a year or so and see how the list has changed.
Here we go, in order they currently appear in my podcast app:
 A Responsive Web Design Podcast — I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Details</title>
      <link>https://iamsim.me/design-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 17:38:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iamsim.me/design-details/</guid>
      <description>Just wanted to write a quick post about one of my new favorite podcasts: Design Details! In which Brian Lovin and Bryn Jackson sit down and talk to fantastic designers. About design and life and what not. I&amp;rsquo;m not a designer myself, but it&amp;rsquo;s really enlightening to hear smart people talk about the subject.
What makes this show special is that all interviews are done in person. Which I believe adds another dimension to the show, compared to podcasts where the interview is conducted over Skype or similar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>